<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Icl on Shweata&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/icl/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Icl on Shweata&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.142.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/icl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Week 05| The Day Before My Birthday</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/02-week-06-icl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/02-week-06-icl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I started this tradition of writing to myself on my birthday in 2022, as a way to wrap-up my year and feel proud about how far I had come. Looking back, it was indeed one of the formative years where I was taking baby steps to learn about the world and my abilities. I still remember the 10th of November from 2022, the tired me in green saree finishing of her day at school, deciding to stop by at the library to write. She had dreamt of something big that day, and the following year, her dreams had indeed come true as she celebrated her birthday in Geneva with Peter in 2023.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 00| MSc at Imperial College London</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/02-week-00-icl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/02-week-00-icl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An announcement long due: I am starting my Master&amp;rsquo;s in Science Communication at Imperial College London as a Chevening Scholar :))&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever since I started watching YouTube as a 13-year-old, I had one dream: studying abroad. I used to religiously watch the study-tubers of my time, hoping I would one day have a routine like theirs studying science in universities like Cambridge, Oxford, etc. It is so funny looking back at that naive version of me, she had no idea how difficult chasing that dream would be.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
