<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Life on Shweata&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Life on Shweata&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.142.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chevening Preparation Notes/Tracker</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/chevening-preparation-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/chevening-preparation-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2025-03-12&#34;&gt;2025-03-12&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned in my &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/week-23-to-32/&#34;&gt;catch-up&lt;/a&gt; post, I have been shortlisted for Chevening interview. Ever since I heard the news on the 14th Feb., I have been excited and anxious. However, anxiety is slowly taking over. It&amp;rsquo;s been over a month, and I don&amp;rsquo;t think I have put enough efforts to prepare. I still don&amp;rsquo;t know how I would answer most of the questions. What kind of funny human am I? I really want the scholarship, but I am not able to actively work towards telling my story in the interview. I am overwhelmed by the sheer amount of information and advice online. What to focus on? What is relevant to me? I am also overwhelmed by the difficulty of the challenge ahead of me. With 50 students being selected for the scholarship, my probabilities of getting it is so low. Knowing this piece of information has only inhibited me from preparing for the interview, which as I write out, sounds so counter-intuitive. Shouldn&amp;rsquo;t I be preparing more rigoursly?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 33 | The Young India Fellowship</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/week-33/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/week-33/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2025-03-03-to-2025-03-09&#34;&gt;2025-03-03 to 2025-03-09&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Term 06 has begun. We have &amp;ldquo;Deconstructing Indian Foreign Policy&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;The Welfare State&amp;rdquo;. These courses are very outside of my comfort zone. However, I have not been able to give these courses the time they deserve because of climate and WSCI presentations. I was disappointed by the fact that I did not get to present my climate group assignment; the professor cut me off because we were running late for dinner. Similarly, our WSCI project was also controversial in some sense, but I personally did not receive feedback.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 23 to Week 32 | Young India Fellowship</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/week-23-to-32/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/week-23-to-32/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I meant to write more frequently, however, it seems like I have not managed to be disciplined enough yet again. As it is always the case, a LOT has happened. Any attempt to capture or document these few months would be an unfruitful exercise. Instead, I will quickly summarise some key events before resuming my usual weekly updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;term-4-2024-12-24-to-2025-01-10-making-videos-after-videos&#34;&gt;Term 4 (2024-12-24 to 2025-01-10): Making videos after videos!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After returning, I was immersed into a block-taught course called Visual Storytelling and Cinematic Techniques. Looking back, it was a very useful course. I, for the first time, learnt video production and acting. From direction insights such as camera angles, shot types, cutaways, continuity, to technicalities of video editing&amp;mdash;we learnt it all. Naturally, the classes were quite intense, packed from morning to evening. Additionally, our ELM had added responsibilities of preparing for the India Science Festival, where we were showcasing the board game version of Pralay. I still remember those cold and gloomy winter evenings, when I forced myself to get out of my room to meet the team to discuss the logistics of making the game. It all came together at the very last moment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On 2024</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/on-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/on-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;2024&amp;mdash;the year full of turbulence. After crusing through 2022 and 2023, 2024 felt like a reality check. When I look back on the year, I only see disappointments, rejections, fights, poor health and lost confidence. However, all of the experiences have also taught me life lessons. Hopefully, as a result, I find myself more resilient in the years to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent the first half of the year doing applications, getting rejections and some acceptances. It was stressful to balance work at TIGS and write compelling applications. TIGS sadly never was a fertile ground for my ideas to grow. I felt undervalued and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t deliver my best either. The experience overall made me doubt whether I would make a good science communicator. I also fell sick in March and I never felt healthy since then. After many deliberations I decided to the Young India Fellowship. I was unsure if it was going to be useful and whether I would be able to manage the workload. Giving up my dream of doing a Masters abroad was hard, too.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 22| The Young India Fellowship and Home</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/week-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/week-22/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had one of the most colorful weeks of 2024. December was indeed an interesting curveball I wasn&amp;rsquo;t expecting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2024-12-22&#34;&gt;2024-12-22&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last day of Organizational Dynamics. It started at 0930. The lectures were boring, honestly. In the afternoon, we were given the final group assignment to express our learnings from the course through a creative piece. Although I was initially hesitant, I ended up dancing with the group. It was definitely a memorable experience, and I am super grateful to my team.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 19, 20 and 21| The Young India Fellowship</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/week-19-20-and-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/week-19-20-and-21/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Past 15 days of Organisational Dynamics course has been a mush. I am constantly startled by the fact that it has only been running for the past 15 days. Feels like life has been this 0900 to 1900 grind forever. Simulations, readings, co-education, instructor-led group discussions&amp;mdash;argh, I was always surrounded by people. Some days were great, others weren&amp;rsquo;t. However, it was the very same people who made it easier. I grew closer to my cohort and am finally starting to feel like I belong.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 18| The Young India Fellowship</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/week-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/week-18/</guid>
      <description>Desperate attempt to make the blog up-to date</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 15, 16 and 17| The Young India Fellowship</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/week-15-16-and-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/week-15-16-and-17/</guid>
      <description>Desperate attempt to make the blog up-to date</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 14| The Young India Fellowship</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/week-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/week-14/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Term 03 officially begins. I am excited for the courses this time. We have Microeconomics and The New Geography in the Information Age (NGIA) &amp;ndash; a funky name but it is a course on information in the age of internet. This week features me singing, reading a lot, working on Chevening Application, spending time with the cohort and having quality time with Karthik.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2024-10-28&#34;&gt;2024-10-28&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First day of Term 03. We had to back-to-back lectures. Woke up early, made it to class 20 minutes before it started. Prof. A. K. Shivkumar from Harvard is teaching us Microeconomics. I like his lecture-approach, simple whiteobard and marker style. We were acquainted with the basics of microeconomics. The problems of the society &amp;ndash; what to produce, how to produce them, how much. We discussed the need for intervention of the market &amp;ndash; supply-side and demand-side. We ended with with model of economy. In the last half an hour of the class, we looked at the case study: India in numbers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 13| The Young India Fellowship</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/week-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/week-13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2024-10-21&#34;&gt;2024-10-21&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Woke up early today. Journalled, showered, worked on the Critical Wriitng researched project and journalled even more. The website has finally caught up to the present day. Having been deep into Climate Game work, our ELM team took a break from work, so I spent my time on Chevening application. Drafting these essays is hard. Sometimes you feel great looking at your past work summarised, and at other times you feel stuck, doubting yourself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 11 and 12| The Young India Fellowship</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/week-11-and-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/week-11-and-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Days: 2024-10-07 to 2024-10-20&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Final two weeks of Term 02, Week 11 and 12, were filled with deadlines. As a result, I was stressed, confused, tired, agititated (fought with Karthik quite a lot). I feel like or even have the time to journal as you can tell. But we have made it through. Here&amp;rsquo;s my attempt at recounting key events from the two weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At glance, here was my deadline list. Art Appreciation and Shakespeare combined, I had 5 assignments, a conference presentation (The Tech We Want), meeting with Prof. Vijayraghavan, a scholarship application (I discontinued working on it).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 10| The Young India Fellowship</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/week-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/week-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2024-09-30&#34;&gt;2024-09-30&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the stage reading sessions, I fully read &lt;em&gt;The Tragedy of Romeo and Juliet&lt;/em&gt;. Later in the evening, we had the first lecture where we discussed the play. I finally get how literature classroom discussions work. Prof. Menon only posed questions and kept probing for answers from us. We collectively make sense of the concepts by contributing our understandings. It&amp;rsquo;s very rare for a STEM class to be democratic like that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 09 | The Young India Fellowship</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/week-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/week-09/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since I&amp;rsquo;m writing the account a week later, it&amp;rsquo;ll be brief.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had the last set of Art Appreciation classes. We looked at different art movements &amp;ndash; renaissance to performance art. I performed My Heart Will Go On in the farewell class. I got nervous, yet again. Being around talented people all the time can do that for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent the first half of the week writing the Expression of Interest to have Prof. Vijayraghavan as my mentor at the YIF. I have been an advocate for open science since I learnt about it. But in writing to Prof. Vijayraghavan, I collated by scattered thoughts about open science in India to coherent narrative. I collasced my interests in science communication and open science. Prathima Muniyappa, an alum of the YIF, had told me about thinking in first principles. I finally noticed commonality two separate career trajectories of mine.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 08 | The Young India Fellowship</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/week-08-yif/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/week-08-yif/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2024-09-16&#34;&gt;2024-09-16&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monday began with breakfast in bed and trip to the infirmary. I was told that I might have caught a stomach bug. Slept all day except to eat and shit multiple times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2024-09-17&#34;&gt;2024-09-17&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Repeat of Monday. Spent a lot of time talking to Karthik and scrolling on phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2024-09-18&#34;&gt;2024-09-18&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slept all day again. Felt slightly better. It was interesting how my life was just about surviving one day at a time. I also discovered that social media has changed a lot since I last checked in. I stumbled across a lot of regional &amp;lsquo;content creators&amp;rsquo;. Gone are the days where there was little Indian representation online.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 07 | The Young India Fellowship</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/week-07-yif/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/week-07-yif/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Time is flying! New term from this week. We have two interesting courses, Art Appreciation (by Prof. Anunaya Chaubey) and Shakespeare and the World (Prof. Jonathan Gil Harris and Prof. Madhavi Menon).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;daily-breakdown&#34;&gt;Daily Breakdown&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2024-09-09&#34;&gt;2024-09-09&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had an uncomfortable experience during the first Art Appreciation class. Prof. asked to paint a canvas in an hour, give it a title, make note of challenges and display. I made an embarassingly bad painting. I was almost in tears after looking around and seeing amazing art works. I felt even worse because of how I reacted. I wish I was slightly better at dealing with being sucky at something.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 06 | The Young India Fellowsship</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/week-06-yif/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/week-06-yif/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Week 06 of the YIF. I have been meaning to document learnings since Week 01, but I never found the time. Including a new habit into your schedule takes effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;daily-breakdown&#34;&gt;Daily Breakdown&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2024-09-02-monday&#34;&gt;2024-09-02 (Monday)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;made-my-cv&#34;&gt;Made my CV&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After struggling for many months to perfect my CV, I finally finished creating one. I was asked by a professor to share my CV so he could look for a potential PhD advisor if I&amp;rsquo;m interested in pursuing one. I used &lt;a href=&#34;https://joinsuperset.com/&#34;&gt;Superset CV builder&lt;/a&gt;. Although it was clunky (with edit widget being too small and it taking forever to load), it helped me format my CV and restrict it to a page. I don&amp;rsquo;t know if I&amp;rsquo;ve done a good job at describing my work experience. We were asked to use the PAR Framework (Problem-Action-Result), but I got to lazy and copy-pasted details from my older resumes and modified a bit for consistency.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 0 | Young India Fellowship</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/week-00-yif/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/week-00-yif/</guid>
      <description>How does a missed week feel like? Not great.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Gap Year</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/on-the-gap-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/on-the-gap-year/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In July 2022, all my undergrad classmates were hustling to figure out Masters, jobs, etc.  On the other hand, I boldly decided to take a year off. No plans. A year for myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus the adventurous journey began, journey that took me to 5 big cities, and taught me life and career lessons. I am documenting experiences here for the future me to look back on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;gandhinagar-curiosity-conference&#34;&gt;Gandhinagar, Curiosity Conference&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First trip of the gap year. Curiosity Conference at IIT Gandhinagar.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m a Young India Fellow</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/young-india-fellowship/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/young-india-fellowship/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yay! I got selected to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ashoka.edu.in/academic-programme/young-india-fellowship/&#34;&gt;Young India Fellowship (YIF)&lt;/a&gt; 2025. Taking a gap year after undergrad was risky, but I&amp;rsquo;m happy that it led me to the YIF. In a month&amp;rsquo;s time, I will be back to being a student. Probably for the first time, my education will be worthy of time and investment. What sold YIF for me is an that it&amp;rsquo;s all-in-one package. I&amp;rsquo;m learning history, economics, statistics, astrophysics, climate, leadership, writing, and many other disciplines and skills. And my peers are fully committed to the Fellowship, it seemed like! During my undergrad, none of us really wanted to learn from our classes. We didn&amp;rsquo;t engage in critical discussions or bother putting any efforts into assignments.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Random Day at BLiSc</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/blisc-lessons/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/blisc-lessons/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today&amp;rsquo;s weather was weird. The sun was not fully out in the morning. It suddenly rained in the afternoon. Later, the sun shone bright for a while before the pouring rain hit the ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took this picture late afternoon before the second rain. Funnily, I had never fully explored this part of the Old NCBS building. They have nice outdoor spaces!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I took the picture, I realised how my time here at the BLiSc campus resembles today&amp;rsquo;s weather. I had a gloomy start, things went downhill, but I pulled myself back up for some sunshine moments, and now it&amp;rsquo;s back to being gloomy again. It&amp;rsquo;s been a wild three months. Living alone, exploring by myself, making and losing acquaintances, pulling together an international trip from scratch, running the podcast, navigating new workspace and tasks, and doing applications. No wonder I feel overwhelmed. But like there is beauty in these rain-soaked flowers facing the somewhat blue sky, there is one in my struggles and successes, too. I&amp;rsquo;ll have to keep chugging along. I&amp;rsquo;m grateful to this place for its lessons.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leave and Let Live</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/leave-and-let-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/leave-and-let-live/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m in the middle of the exam season. I have an exam in two hours. But here I am, sitting on my bed facing the same pink curtain and the fairy light, reflecting on my time in Room No. 122. In a week, the room won&amp;rsquo;t be mine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but wonder about the stories the room holds, stories that I (or anyone who comes next) will never know. The hostel is close to 70 years old, which means more than 150 people lived in this room before me. And every person, inevitably, must have filled the room with have been filled with laughter, heartbreaks, gossip, love stories, fights, and more.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
