<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Term-03 on Shweata&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/term-03/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Term-03 on Shweata&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.142.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/term-03/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Week 18| The Young India Fellowship</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/week-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/week-18/</guid>
      <description>Desperate attempt to make the blog up-to date</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Term 03 | The New Geography of Information Age | Extension Notes 06: Is Censorship the Right Way to Go? Science Communication Perspective</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/assignments/term-03-ngia-essay-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/assignments/term-03-ngia-essay-07/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Given our conversation in class about the complex issue of censorship on social media, I explored the role of censorship in science communication. At first glance, one might argue that removing non-factual content, such as &amp;ldquo;vaccines cause autism&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;plant X has proven to cure Y disease,&amp;rdquo; might be the best option to prevent its further spread. However, the problem is that non-factual content is complicated and takes many forms—misinformation, disinformation, and conspiracy theories—all of which require different approaches to address.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 15, 16 and 17| The Young India Fellowship</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/week-15-16-and-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/week-15-16-and-17/</guid>
      <description>Desperate attempt to make the blog up-to date</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Term 03 | The New Geography of Information Age | Extension Notes 06: My Aadhar Story</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/assignments/term-03-ngia-essay-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/assignments/term-03-ngia-essay-06/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a family, we seldom went out to the town together; naturally, whenever we did, it was memorable. One such event was registering for our Aadhar cards. One day after school, my parents and I went to a registration center near the famous temple in the town. I had no idea what Aadhar was, and my parents did not explain it either. It was a small shop with benches, and it was unusually crowded. As a jumpy 10-year-old, I did not want to wait. Hours passed. When our turn finally came, I realized why the process took so long: the biometrics. People had to try multiple times before their biometrics were recorded. Of course, this was in the early days, somewhere around 2010, and the process, I am sure, is a lot smoother now.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Term 03 | The New Geography of Information Age | Extension Notes 05: Split Brain Experiment: Is it Oversimplified?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/assignments/term-03-ngia-essay-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/assignments/term-03-ngia-essay-05/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As someone who studied biology during undergrad, I was surprised to have not heard about the Split Brain Experiment (which probably shows my slight disinterest in neuroscience). Prof. Debayan’s descriptions of patients behaving oddly after their callosotomy—a procedure disconnecting the two halves of the brain—made me probe further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Searching YouTube landed me on the most &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wfYbgdo8e-8&#34;&gt;popular video&lt;/a&gt; on this topic by the CGP Grey channel. It described the experiments conducted in the late 19th century on split-brain patients by Sperry et al., which revealed the different specializations of the left and right hemispheres of the brain, a phenomenon known as lateralization. However, I found certain phrasings in the video questionable. Specifically, it claimed that “you are two,” meaning that there are two separate minds in an individual—the linguistic “left brain” and visual-processing “right brain.” It speculates that, in non-split-brain individuals, the “right brain rose up as a companion without a choice.” The video ends with a deeply unsettling thought: “At this moment, in your normal head, there are two of you watching this video: one having a &amp;lsquo;mind-blown&amp;rsquo; moment, and the other mentally rolling its eyes at the obviousness of it all.” I found this perspective—that there are two separate conscious agents—somewhat misinterpreting the experiments.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Term 03 | The New Geography of Information Age | Extension Notes 04: Anti-vaxxers---Where Are They</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/assignments/term-03-ngia-essay-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/assignments/term-03-ngia-essay-04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;anti-vaxxers----where-are-they&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anti-Vaxxers &amp;ndash; Where Are They?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Decades of research show that vaccines save lives. However, there are communities of people known as anti-vaxxers who hesitate or refuse to get vaccinated. When faced with devastating pandemics like COVID-19, this &amp;ldquo;vaccine hesitancy&amp;rdquo; poses a threat to humanity. The advent of social media has only complicated the issue, providing opportunities for anti-vaxxers to spread misinformation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of the Extension Notes, I looked at YouTube comments on:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Term 03 | The New Geography of Information Age | Extension Notes 03: Reviewing &#39;Mother of All Demos&#39;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/assignments/term-03-ngia-essay-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/assignments/term-03-ngia-essay-03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Having given a few tech demos, Prof. Debayan’s mention of Douglas Engelbart&amp;rsquo;s “Mother of All Demos (1968)” made me curious to watch it. The presentation was given at a conference in conjunction with a conference paper titled “A Research Center for Augmenting Human Intellect.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/UhpTiWyVa6k?si=Sya6XDw4omvSxCjt&amp;amp;start=1&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Engelbart showcased the oNLine System&amp;rsquo;s (NLS) features, such as file systems, text editors, and so on. He mentioned that his team used the consoles for “daily work,” perhaps making these the first-ever personal computers. It was interesting to see the seeds of what has now shaped current computers and the web, including hyperlinks, low-level and high-level languages, version control (bug and change trackers), compilers, file management, information retrieval, video conferencing, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Term 03 | The New Geography of Information Age | Extension Notes 02: Blockchain for Scientific Publishing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/assignments/term-03-ngia-essay-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/assignments/term-03-ngia-essay-02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After listening to Prof. Debayan explain blockchain, I started looking for avenues, apart from cryptocurrencies, where such a decentralized system could be used. Previously, as part of a research project, I had spent a considerable amount of time understanding the current scientific publishing ecosystem, only to realize that it lacks transparency and is gatekept by a few companies. Further, the competitive nature of scientific publishing has caused nuanced problems, such as p-hacking, data fudging, and the reproducibility crisis. Since publishing is vital to the scientific process, I wondered if blockchain technology could solve some of these problems.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Term 03 | The New Geography of Information Age | Extension Notes 01:  How Do They Know All About Me?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/assignments/term-03-ngia-essay-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/assignments/term-03-ngia-essay-01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Understanding Big Data Analysis Behind Recommender Systems and Other Algorithms&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite friends discussing targeted advertising and giant companies tracking online activities, I had not bothered learning more about cookies or user profiling. I knew enough to ensure I checked the “Reject All” option whenever I visited a website, but I did not know the implications of not doing so. As Prof. Debayan explained how ad companies such as DoubleClick track me across websites to gather insights about my preferences and thereby show relevant advertisements, I became aware of my ignorance. I also realized that targeted advertising involves analyzing huge amounts of data and became curious to learn more about it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 14| The Young India Fellowship</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/week-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/week-14/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Term 03 officially begins. I am excited for the courses this time. We have Microeconomics and The New Geography in the Information Age (NGIA) &amp;ndash; a funky name but it is a course on information in the age of internet. This week features me singing, reading a lot, working on Chevening Application, spending time with the cohort and having quality time with Karthik.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2024-10-28&#34;&gt;2024-10-28&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First day of Term 03. We had to back-to-back lectures. Woke up early, made it to class 20 minutes before it started. Prof. A. K. Shivkumar from Harvard is teaching us Microeconomics. I like his lecture-approach, simple whiteobard and marker style. We were acquainted with the basics of microeconomics. The problems of the society &amp;ndash; what to produce, how to produce them, how much. We discussed the need for intervention of the market &amp;ndash; supply-side and demand-side. We ended with with model of economy. In the last half an hour of the class, we looked at the case study: India in numbers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
