<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Term-03 on Shweata&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/term-03/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Term-03 on Shweata&#39;s Blog</description>
    <image>
      <title>Shweata&#39;s Blog</title>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/images/papermod-cover.png</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/images/papermod-cover.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.3</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/term-03/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Term 03 | The New Geography of Information Age | Extension Notes 01:  How Do They Know All About Me?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/assignments/term-03-ngia-essay-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/assignments/term-03-ngia-essay-01/</guid>
      <description>Understanding Big Data Analysis Behind Recommender Systems and Other Algorithms
Despite friends discussing targeted advertising and giant companies tracking online activities, I had not bothered learning more about cookies or user profiling. I knew enough to ensure I checked the “Reject All” option whenever I visited a website, but I did not know the implications of not doing so. As Prof. Debayan explained how ad companies such as DoubleClick track me across websites to gather insights about my preferences and thereby show relevant advertisements, I became aware of my ignorance.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Term 03 | The New Geography of Information Age | Extension Notes 02: Blockchain for Scientific Publishing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/assignments/term-03-ngia-essay-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/assignments/term-03-ngia-essay-02/</guid>
      <description>After listening to Prof. Debayan explain blockchain, I started looking for avenues, apart from cryptocurrencies, where such a decentralized system could be used. Previously, as part of a research project, I had spent a considerable amount of time understanding the current scientific publishing ecosystem, only to realize that it lacks transparency and is gatekept by a few companies. Further, the competitive nature of scientific publishing has caused nuanced problems, such as p-hacking, data fudging, and the reproducibility crisis.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Term 03 | The New Geography of Information Age | Extension Notes 03: Reviewing &#39;Mother of All Demos&#39;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/assignments/term-03-ngia-essay-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/assignments/term-03-ngia-essay-03/</guid>
      <description>Reviewing “Mother of All Demos” Having given a few tech demos, Prof. Debayan’s mention of Douglas Engelbart&amp;rsquo;s “Mother of All Demos (1968)” made me curious to watch it. The presentation was given at a conference in conjunction with a conference paper titled “A Research Center for Augmenting Human Intellect.”
Engelbart showcased the oNLine System&amp;rsquo;s (NLS) features, such as file systems, text editors, and so on. He mentioned that his team used the consoles for “daily work,” perhaps making these the first-ever personal computers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 15, 16 and 17| The Young India Fellowship</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/week-15-16-and17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/week-15-16-and17/</guid>
      <description>Desperate attempt to make the blog up-to date</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 14| The Young India Fellowship</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/week-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/week-14/</guid>
      <description>Term 03 officially begins. I am excited for the courses this time. We have Microeconomics and The New Geography in the Information Age (NGIA) &amp;ndash; a funky name but it is a course on information in the age of internet. This week features me singing, reading a lot, working on Chevening Application, spending time with the cohort and having quality time with Karthik.
2024-10-28 First day of Term 03. We had to back-to-back lectures.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
