<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Shweata&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Shweata&#39;s Blog</description>
    <image>
      <title>Shweata&#39;s Blog</title>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/images/papermod-cover.png</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/images/papermod-cover.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.3</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Gap Year</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/on-the-gap-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/on-the-gap-year/</guid>
      <description>In July 2022, all my undergrad classmates were hustling to figure out Masters, jobs, etc. On the other hand, I boldly decided to take a year off. No plans. A year for myself.
Thus the adventurous journey began, journey that took me to 5 big cities, and taught me life and career lessons. I am documenting experiences here for the future me to look back on.
Gandhinagar, Curiosity Conference First trip of the gap year.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m a Young India Fellow 2025</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/young-india-fellowship/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/young-india-fellowship/</guid>
      <description>Yay! I got selected for the Young India Fellowship (YIF) 2025. Taking a gap year after undergrad was risky, but I&amp;rsquo;m happy that it led me to the YIF. In a month&amp;rsquo;s time, I will be back to being a student. Probably for the first time, my education will be worthy of time and investment. What sold YIF for me is an that it&amp;rsquo;s all-in-one package. I&amp;rsquo;m learning history, economics, statistics, astrophysics, climate, leadership, writing, and many other disciplines and skills.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 0 | Young India Fellowship</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/week-0-yif/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/week-0-yif/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Random Day at BLiSc</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/blisc-lessons/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/blisc-lessons/</guid>
      <description>Today&amp;rsquo;s weather was weird. The sun was not fully out in the morning. It suddenly rained in the afternoon. Later, the sun shone bright for a while before the pouring rain hit the ground.
I took this picture late afternoon before the second rain. Funnily, I had never fully explored this part of the Old NCBS building. They have nice outdoor spaces!
As I took the picture, I realised how my time here at the BLiSc campus resembles today&amp;rsquo;s weather.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leave and Let Live</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/leave-and-let-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/leave-and-let-live/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m in the middle of the exam season. I have an exam in two hours. But here I am, sitting on my bed facing the same pink curtain and the fairy light, reflecting on my time in Room No. 122. In a week, the room won&amp;rsquo;t be mine.
I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but wonder about the stories the room holds, stories that I (or anyone who comes next) will never know. The hostel is close to 70 years old, which means more than 150 people lived in this room before me.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
