<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Shweata&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Shweata&#39;s Blog</description>
    <image>
      <title>Shweata&#39;s Blog</title>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/images/papermod-cover.png</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/images/papermod-cover.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.3</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Critical Writing Assignment 01 | Our Emotions Around Languages</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/term-01-cw-on-emotions-and-languages-assignment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/term-01-cw-on-emotions-and-languages-assignment/</guid>
      <description>After living in Mysore (a quiet city in Karnataka) for most of my life, I moved to Bengaluru last year for work. Naturally, I bumped into more non-kannada-speaking folks than usual, and English became my go-to language. Nothing to fret about. All my life I’ve enjoyed speaking in English. I took pride in being fluent in the language at school and even college. I often said I think in English. I had no issues giving presentations, making points in meetings, or having casual conversations at the workplace.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Term 01 | Leadership Assignments</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/term-01-leadership-assignments/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/term-01-leadership-assignments/</guid>
      <description>One of the assignments was to make a video about ourself. I was quite apprehensive at first. But I realised it&amp;rsquo;s a good practice to concisely tell a story about yourself. This is my attempt at telling a story about how I got into science communication.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Term 01 | Statistics Group Assignments</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/term-01-stats-group-assignments/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/term-01-stats-group-assignments/</guid>
      <description>Over the course, we had 4 group assignments, which required us to use statistical tools like z-score, t-test, chi-squared test, etc in various scenarios. I decided to use Python to do all analyses. Looking back, it was a nice way to practice coding while also learning new concepts.
Notebook Links Assignment 01 (Kilgore Production Analysis): https://gist.github.com/ShweataNHegde/a4203e663b0f1cea6cb9c52e35258a1c Assignment 02 (Pronto Delivery): https://gist.github.com/ShweataNHegde/abd7b814af4c16cd376747fdf35f2dac Assignment 03 (Cyril Burt: Fraud or Not?): https://gist.github.com/ShweataNHegde/d421bb33b3f77c06b8023d179266b55a Assignment 04 (Teachers Fraud?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 07 | The Young India Fellowship</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/week-07-yif/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/week-07-yif/</guid>
      <description>Time is flying! New term from this week. We have two interesting courses, Art Appreciation (by Prof. Anunaya Chaubey) and Shakespeare and the World (Prof. Jonathan Gil Harris and Prof. Madhavi Menon).
Daily Breakdown 2024-09-09 I had an uncomfortable experience during the first Art Appreciation class. Prof. asked to paint a canvas in an hour, give it a title, make note of challenges and display. I made an embarassingly bad painting.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Term 01| Statistics Individual Assignment</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/term-01-stats-ind-assignment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/term-01-stats-ind-assignment/</guid>
      <description>Through the course, I learnt about various statistical tools and concept. But I also explored how to run them in Python. So, it only makes sense for my final report to be an interactive Python file.
# Import packages from scipy.stats import norm import matplotlib.pyplot as plt import numpy as np import random import seaborn as sns Part A Choose three of the four following statistical tools (A.1 – A.4). For each of your chosen three, write a short response exhibiting your understanding of the tool (250 words maximum each).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 06 | The Young India Fellowsship</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/week-06-yif/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/week-06-yif/</guid>
      <description>Week 06 of the YIF. I have been meaning to document learnings since Week 01, but I never found the time. Including a new habit into your schedule takes effort.
Daily Breakdown 2024-09-02 (Monday) Made my CV After struggling for many months to perfect my CV, I finally finished creating one. I was asked by a professor to share my CV so he could look for a potential PhD advisor if I&amp;rsquo;m interested in pursuing one.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 0 | Young India Fellowship</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/week-00-yif/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/week-00-yif/</guid>
      <description>How does a missed week feel like? Not great.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Gap Year</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/on-the-gap-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/on-the-gap-year/</guid>
      <description>In July 2022, all my undergrad classmates were hustling to figure out Masters, jobs, etc. On the other hand, I boldly decided to take a year off. No plans. A year for myself.
Thus the adventurous journey began, journey that took me to 5 big cities, and taught me life and career lessons. I am documenting experiences here for the future me to look back on.
Gandhinagar, Curiosity Conference First trip of the gap year.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m a Young India Fellow</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/young-india-fellowship/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/young-india-fellowship/</guid>
      <description>Yay! I got selected to the Young India Fellowship (YIF) 2025. Taking a gap year after undergrad was risky, but I&amp;rsquo;m happy that it led me to the YIF. In a month&amp;rsquo;s time, I will be back to being a student. Probably for the first time, my education will be worthy of time and investment. What sold YIF for me is an that it&amp;rsquo;s all-in-one package. I&amp;rsquo;m learning history, economics, statistics, astrophysics, climate, leadership, writing, and many other disciplines and skills.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Random Day at BLiSc</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/blisc-lessons/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/blisc-lessons/</guid>
      <description>Today&amp;rsquo;s weather was weird. The sun was not fully out in the morning. It suddenly rained in the afternoon. Later, the sun shone bright for a while before the pouring rain hit the ground.
I took this picture late afternoon before the second rain. Funnily, I had never fully explored this part of the Old NCBS building. They have nice outdoor spaces!
As I took the picture, I realised how my time here at the BLiSc campus resembles today&amp;rsquo;s weather.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leave and Let Live</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/leave-and-let-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/leave-and-let-live/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m in the middle of the exam season. I have an exam in two hours. But here I am, sitting on my bed facing the same pink curtain and the fairy light, reflecting on my time in Room No. 122. In a week, the room won&amp;rsquo;t be mine.
I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but wonder about the stories the room holds, stories that I (or anyone who comes next) will never know. The hostel is close to 70 years old, which means more than 150 people lived in this room before me.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
