<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Term-07 on Shweata&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/term-07/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Term-07 on Shweata&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.142.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/term-07/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Term 07 | Language, Politics, and Society in India | In Dialogue with LSI</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/assignments/term-07-language-politics-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/assignments/term-07-language-politics-02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;embed src=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1ABgTkDlMEPok1vByjIVyd2A4FjWIEsgH/view?usp=sharing&#34; type=&#34;application/pdf&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; /&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Term 07 | Language, Politics, and Society in India | Kannada Lesson With Ajji</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/assignments/term-07-language-politics-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/assignments/term-07-language-politics-01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, I came across a series of Instagram Reels on a Bharatanatyam dancer’s offshoot account. In the series, she plays the character of a Kannadiga ajji, a grandmother, who teaches non-Kannadigas the usage of specific ‘colloquial’ Kannada words (Calling out my own language ideology—what constitutes colloquial as opposed to formal/standard? I do not have an answer).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In one such video (ruks_avatars)—which one could call a metapragmatic discourse—she first teaches the literal usage of chatri, a Kannada word that means umbrella. Secondly, she asks what the term “dummukuchatri” (transliterates to jumping umbrella) means. Dummukuchatri is a seldom used word, which means parachute; one could call this an attempt to prevent the erasure of certain infrequently used Kannada words. Finally, she describes chatri’s property to “keep turning, round, round, round” and iconises the word by saying “this is the same quality of a chatri person”, referring to people who cannot be trusted. Going further, the ajji character’s language and conversation with the audience is indexical of a ‘typical progressive nit-picky, complaining’ grandmother (this could very well be my own iconisation, too). She is well-versed in English and knows how to communicate and translate Kannada words. However, this typical representation can also be seen as an erasure of the existence of other ajjis.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 43 and 44 | The Young India Fellowship</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/week-43-and-44/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/week-43-and-44/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have taken to swimming! I probably should have updated here sooner. In the beginning of May, Arushi convinced me to get swimdress and go to pool. The first day was the scariest. It was almost as if I had forgotten how the body feels when it&amp;rsquo;s inside something that is 100 times more dense than the air it is used to. But over the weeks, I have gotten better. I can kick and propel forward. I have been doing breathing drills; hopefully I will be able to combine all these and learn to swim soon. Swimming is one of the few things that has given me back the joy of learning.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 42 | The Young India Fellowship</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/week-42/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/week-42/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I never quite managed to post here again, despite having a rather light term. Times have changed very much. I think it&amp;rsquo;s safe to say that I don&amp;rsquo;t think I will ever have a &amp;rsquo;normal&amp;rsquo; educational experience, without any global challenges jeopardising it. India-Pakistan conflict has intensified over the last week. My heart goes out to all the people the bordering regions on both sides. Although I am priveleged enough to not having to worry about a missile hitting my building (not yet, at least), I still can&amp;rsquo;t help but be anxious, consume as much news as possible. I want to go back home. I am worried that I might get landlocked if I don&amp;rsquo;t act swiftly. But, on the other hand, I feel guilty whenever thoughts of fleeing down to the south comes to mind. What about those who don&amp;rsquo;t have the option of traveling back home? What of those who cannot afford to go back home? I feel selfish for choosing me over others.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 38 | The Young India Fellowship</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/week-38/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/week-38/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2025-04-15&#34;&gt;2025-04-15&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new term finally began :) After tireless days working on ELM presentations, game nights, interviews, essays and assignments, we made it out of the busiest period of the Fellowship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was really excited (I still am) for all three of my courses:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design Thinking and Innovation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Language Politics and Society&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sustainable Development: How Can We Align Social Justice, Biodiversity Conservation and Climate Action&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think this will be one of my favourite terms after term 01 where we had statistics and history.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
