<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Term-05 on Shweata&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/term-05/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Term-05 on Shweata&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.142.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/term-05/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Week 23 to Week 32</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/week-23-to-32/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/week-23-to-32/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I meant to write more frequently, however, it seems like I have not managed to be disciplined enough yet again. As it is always the case, a LOT has happened. Any attempt to capture or document these few months would be an unfruitful exercise. Instead, I will quickly summarise some key events before resuming my usual weekly updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;term-4-2024-12-24-to-2025-01-10-making-videos-after-videos&#34;&gt;Term 4 (2024-12-24 to 2025-01-10): Making videos after videos!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After returning, I was immersed into a block-taught course called Visual Storytelling and Cinematic Techniques. Looking back, it was a very useful course. I, for the first time, learnt video production and acting. From direction insights such as camera angles, shot types, cutaways, continuity, to technicalities of video editing&amp;mdash;we learnt it all. Naturally, the classes were quite intense, packed from morning to evening. Additionally, our ELM had added responsibilities of preparing for the India Science Festival, where we were showcasing the board game version of Pralay. I still remember those cold and gloomy winter evenings, when I forced myself to get out of my room to meet the team to discuss the logistics of making the game. It all came together at the very last moment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
