<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Break on Shweata&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/break/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Break on Shweata&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.142.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/break/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>On 2024</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/on-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/on-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;2024&amp;mdash;the year full of turbulence. After crusing through 2022 and 2023, 2024 felt like a reality check. When I look back on the year, I only see disappointments, rejections, fights, poor health and lost confidence. However, all of the experiences have also taught me life lessons. Hopefully, as a result, I find myself more resilient in the years to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent the first half of the year doing applications, getting rejections and some acceptances. It was stressful to balance work at TIGS and write compelling applications. TIGS sadly never was a fertile ground for my ideas to grow. I felt undervalued and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t deliver my best either. The experience overall made me doubt whether I would make a good science communicator. I also fell sick in March and I never felt healthy since then. After many deliberations I decided to the Young India Fellowship. I was unsure if it was going to be useful and whether I would be able to manage the workload. Giving up my dream of doing a Masters abroad was hard, too.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 22| The Young India Fellowship and Home</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/week-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/week-22/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;had one of the most colorful weeks of 2024. December was indeed an interesting curveball I wasn&amp;rsquo;t expecting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2024-12-22&#34;&gt;2024-12-22&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last day of Organizational Dynamics. It started at 09:30. The lectures were boring, honestly. In the afternoon, we were given the final group assignment to express our learnings from the course through a creative piece. Although I was initially hesitant, I ended up dancing with the group. It was definitely a memorable experience, and I am super grateful to my team.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
