<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Assignments on Shweata&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/assignments/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Assignments on Shweata&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.142.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/assignments/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Term 06 | Can Scientific Temperament Help Build a Better Welfare State?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/assignments/term-06-the-welfare-state/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/assignments/term-06-the-welfare-state/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most rhetoric about the welfare state revolves around the mechanics and politics of schemes related to social protection, social assistance, and social rights such as—education, healthcare, food, and employment. However, abstracting our way out from this detailed perspective and instead looking at the Welfare State as a whole, we realise that “the welfare state is a distinctive form of governmentality: a specific mode of constituting the economy, assuring social security, and guaranteeing social provision (Garland, D., 2014)”. In this essay, I argue that scientific temperament should be one of the core pillars—if not the pillar—of this form of governmentality.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Term 06 | Op-Ed | India&#39;s Foreign Policy | Need for a Science Policy Discourse in Formal Research Spaces</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/assignments/term-06-foreign-policy-op-ed-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/assignments/term-06-foreign-policy-op-ed-01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a student of science and education at a government college, I had no encouragement to keep up with current affairs. After all, my tasks were that of “pure science” like running experiments in labs. However, as years passed, I started having a more outward look, beyond the lab, and realised that science happens not in isolation. The very establishment where I perform experiments is shaped by societal context, and most importantly, local, national and global politics. For instance, if the funding agencies decided to cut funding to my institution, I would not have the chemicals to perform experiments.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Term 06 | Op-Ed | India&#39;s Foreign Policy | Wildlife To Bring Together India and Pakistan?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/assignments/term-06-foreign-policy-op-ed-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/assignments/term-06-foreign-policy-op-ed-02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“Twin orphaned bear cubs given shelter near India-Pakistan border”, read a Reuters News headline. In 2021, two Asiatic Bear cubs were found on the Pakistani side of Kashmir. Unable to open their eyes, the cubs could barely manage to crawl away from the border. Their mother? She was never to be found on the Pakistani side; she was probably killed at the Indian border, either due to the fencing or landmines. The long-standing disputes between India and Pakistan have led to the two countries taking extreme measures; the electric fence being one of them. The fencing of the Line Of Control (LoC) completed in 2004 was meant to prevent the illegal entry of militants. But it has inadvertently also caused incredible damage to habitats at the border—spanning cold deserts, mountains and hot deserts. Locals and forest officials on both sides of the border recount countless stories of lost wildlife—such as separated cubs, deer injured by landmines, or leopards killed for human safety—all as a direct consequence of border control and fencing. But who is to listen? Both countries are too busy strategising their next wars or attacks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Term 06 | The Welfare State | Critical Reading Notes on Bread For All (Introduction)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/assignments/term-06-the-welfare-state-critical-notes-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/assignments/term-06-the-welfare-state-critical-notes-02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Reading excerpts from Bread For All by Chris Renwick was my first introduction to Social History. I found Social History fascinating because it weaves together the lived experiences of people from the past. What piqued my interest was how there are certain culminating events in history—such as the Beveridge Report becoming popular—but the event in itself does not tell us the whole story. It is only when we situate that event in the mundane of every day and look at the ideas of the time, does the real picture of the past emerges. In that regard, I was drawn to the work of journalist Charles Madge, the anthropologist Tom Harrisson, and the filmmaker Humphrey Jennings in documenting the “Collective unconscious” through  “Mass-Observations”.  In particular, there was this statement on why British people, particularly middle-class people, were having smaller families than they had in the past, which read: “People lacked faith in the future. Not a belief that things are going to be tough, and it will take a long time to get right &amp;hellip; But a belief that nobody’s going to try and put things right and improve them, that the nation is going to muddle on through the chaoses [sic] of another 1919–39 to another world war in 1965.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Term 06 | The Welfare State | Critical Reading Notes On Right to Healthcare in Times of Universal Health Coverage</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/assignments/term-06-the-welfare-state-critical-notes-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/assignments/term-06-the-welfare-state-critical-notes-01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At my previous workplace, I was involved in public health communication for rare genetic diseases. Our team’s table read of the National Policy for Rare Diseases (NPRD), 2021, exposed me to the intricacies of India’s present-day healthcare system. We had extensive discussions about how essential services—such as genetic counseling, newborn screening, and early detection of non-communicable diseases—should be part of the Primary Health Care (PHC) system. Adding to these conversations was The India Forum article, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theindiaforum.in/health/right-healthcare-times-universal-health-coverage&#34;&gt;Right to Healthcare in Times of Universal Health Coverage&lt;/a&gt;, which gave me a framework to think about and possibly reimagine the healthcare system.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Term 05 | Climate Change: The Challenge of Communication</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/assignments/term-05-climate-and-geopolitics-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/assignments/term-05-climate-and-geopolitics-paper/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For my final term assignment for the Climate and Geopolitics course at the Young India Fellowship, I was doing some readings about the likelihood of exceeding the maximum wet-bulb temperature (the measure of the combination temperature and humidity) due to anthropogenic climate change. The papers were technical, however, I knew enough scientific jargon to grasp the apocalypse predicted. One of the papers read, “under RCP8.5, a small fraction of the South Asian population (~4%) is projected to experience TWmax [maximum wet bulb temperature] exceeding 35°C by 2100. However, approximately 75% of the population is projected to experience TWmax exceeding 31°C, considered dangerous levels for most humans…” (Im et al.). This made me wonder: Are the people living in the regions-to-be-affected aware of the future they are about to face, let alone be prepared? Worse, “the geographical locations of the most extreme projected heat waves in the Indus and Ganges river valleys coincide largely with locations of highly vulnerable human populations in terms of population density, gross domestic product (GDP) per capita, and agricultural intensity” (Im et al.). How does one even talk about future projections when these vulnerable communities have more immediate problems of livelihood and survival to deal with in the present?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Term 03 | The New Geography of Information Age | Extension Notes 06: Is Censorship the Right Way to Go? Science Communication Perspective</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/assignments/term-03-ngia-essay-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/assignments/term-03-ngia-essay-07/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Given our conversation in class about the complex issue of censorship on social media, I explored the role of censorship in science communication. At first glance, one might argue that removing non-factual content, such as &amp;ldquo;vaccines cause autism&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;plant X has proven to cure Y disease,&amp;rdquo; might be the best option to prevent its further spread. However, the problem is that non-factual content is complicated and takes many forms—misinformation, disinformation, and conspiracy theories—all of which require different approaches to address.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Term 03 | The New Geography of Information Age | Extension Notes 06: My Aadhar Story</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/assignments/term-03-ngia-essay-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/assignments/term-03-ngia-essay-06/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a family, we seldom went out to the town together; naturally, whenever we did, it was memorable. One such event was registering for our Aadhar cards. One day after school, my parents and I went to a registration center near the famous temple in the town. I had no idea what Aadhar was, and my parents did not explain it either. It was a small shop with benches, and it was unusually crowded. As a jumpy 10-year-old, I did not want to wait. Hours passed. When our turn finally came, I realized why the process took so long: the biometrics. People had to try multiple times before their biometrics were recorded. Of course, this was in the early days, somewhere around 2010, and the process, I am sure, is a lot smoother now.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Term 03 | The New Geography of Information Age | Extension Notes 05: Split Brain Experiment: Is it Oversimplified?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/assignments/term-03-ngia-essay-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/assignments/term-03-ngia-essay-05/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As someone who studied biology during undergrad, I was surprised to have not heard about the Split Brain Experiment (which probably shows my slight disinterest in neuroscience). Prof. Debayan’s descriptions of patients behaving oddly after their callosotomy—a procedure disconnecting the two halves of the brain—made me probe further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Searching YouTube landed me on the most &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wfYbgdo8e-8&#34;&gt;popular video&lt;/a&gt; on this topic by the CGP Grey channel. It described the experiments conducted in the late 19th century on split-brain patients by Sperry et al., which revealed the different specializations of the left and right hemispheres of the brain, a phenomenon known as lateralization. However, I found certain phrasings in the video questionable. Specifically, it claimed that “you are two,” meaning that there are two separate minds in an individual—the linguistic “left brain” and visual-processing “right brain.” It speculates that, in non-split-brain individuals, the “right brain rose up as a companion without a choice.” The video ends with a deeply unsettling thought: “At this moment, in your normal head, there are two of you watching this video: one having a &amp;lsquo;mind-blown&amp;rsquo; moment, and the other mentally rolling its eyes at the obviousness of it all.” I found this perspective—that there are two separate conscious agents—somewhat misinterpreting the experiments.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Term 03 | The New Geography of Information Age | Extension Notes 04: Anti-vaxxers---Where Are They</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/assignments/term-03-ngia-essay-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/assignments/term-03-ngia-essay-04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;anti-vaxxers----where-are-they&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anti-Vaxxers &amp;ndash; Where Are They?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Decades of research show that vaccines save lives. However, there are communities of people known as anti-vaxxers who hesitate or refuse to get vaccinated. When faced with devastating pandemics like COVID-19, this &amp;ldquo;vaccine hesitancy&amp;rdquo; poses a threat to humanity. The advent of social media has only complicated the issue, providing opportunities for anti-vaxxers to spread misinformation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of the Extension Notes, I looked at YouTube comments on:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Term 03 | The New Geography of Information Age | Extension Notes 03: Reviewing &#39;Mother of All Demos&#39;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/assignments/term-03-ngia-essay-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/assignments/term-03-ngia-essay-03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Having given a few tech demos, Prof. Debayan’s mention of Douglas Engelbart&amp;rsquo;s “Mother of All Demos (1968)” made me curious to watch it. The presentation was given at a conference in conjunction with a conference paper titled “A Research Center for Augmenting Human Intellect.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/UhpTiWyVa6k?si=Sya6XDw4omvSxCjt&amp;amp;start=1&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Engelbart showcased the oNLine System&amp;rsquo;s (NLS) features, such as file systems, text editors, and so on. He mentioned that his team used the consoles for “daily work,” perhaps making these the first-ever personal computers. It was interesting to see the seeds of what has now shaped current computers and the web, including hyperlinks, low-level and high-level languages, version control (bug and change trackers), compilers, file management, information retrieval, video conferencing, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Term 03 | The New Geography of Information Age | Extension Notes 02: Blockchain for Scientific Publishing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/assignments/term-03-ngia-essay-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/assignments/term-03-ngia-essay-02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After listening to Prof. Debayan explain blockchain, I started looking for avenues, apart from cryptocurrencies, where such a decentralized system could be used. Previously, as part of a research project, I had spent a considerable amount of time understanding the current scientific publishing ecosystem, only to realize that it lacks transparency and is gatekept by a few companies. Further, the competitive nature of scientific publishing has caused nuanced problems, such as p-hacking, data fudging, and the reproducibility crisis. Since publishing is vital to the scientific process, I wondered if blockchain technology could solve some of these problems.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Term 03 | The New Geography of Information Age | Extension Notes 01:  How Do They Know All About Me?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/assignments/term-03-ngia-essay-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/assignments/term-03-ngia-essay-01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Understanding Big Data Analysis Behind Recommender Systems and Other Algorithms&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite friends discussing targeted advertising and giant companies tracking online activities, I had not bothered learning more about cookies or user profiling. I knew enough to ensure I checked the “Reject All” option whenever I visited a website, but I did not know the implications of not doing so. As Prof. Debayan explained how ad companies such as DoubleClick track me across websites to gather insights about my preferences and thereby show relevant advertisements, I became aware of my ignorance. I also realized that targeted advertising involves analyzing huge amounts of data and became curious to learn more about it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Term 02 | Art Appreciation Final Essay | The Power of Scientific Illustrations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/assignments/term-02-art-app-final-essay/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/assignments/term-02-art-app-final-essay/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“To develop a complete mind: Study the science of art; study the art of science. Learn how to see. Realize that everything connects to everything else.” - Leonardo Da Vinci&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a non-artist in biology classes, I was always in awe of botany and zoology professors who drew detailed diagrams of, let’s say, a dissected flower part or insect organ on the chalkboard. The professors captured all the details a photograph would, except that the diagram was better at spotlighting the key characteristics of the specimen. To draw such a detailed diagram, one observes patiently and records — skills valuable to any researcher. Therefore, as biology students, we were encouraged to draw, even if we didn’t come with the skillset of an artist.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Term 02 | Art Appreciation Final Painting</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/assignments/term-02-art-app-final-painting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/assignments/term-02-art-app-final-painting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;circles-and-lines&#34;&gt;Circles and Lines&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Geometric patterns are fascinating; the more you look at them, the more they reveal. Like craftsmen from ancient times, I created this geometric pattern on the canvas by drawing circles and lines. The colours chosen for the motifs uncover various perspectives to observe the pattern. Pause and discover what this pattern reveals to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The geometric pattern painted is adapted from the book, &amp;ldquo;Islamic Geometric Pattern&amp;rdquo; by Eric Broug.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Critical Writing Assignment 01 | Our Emotions Around Languages</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/assignments/term-01-cw-on-emotions-and-languages-assignment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/assignments/term-01-cw-on-emotions-and-languages-assignment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After living in Mysore (a quiet city in Karnataka) for most of my life, I moved to Bengaluru last year for work. Naturally, I bumped into more non-kannada-speaking folks than usual, and English became my go-to language. Nothing to fret about. All my life I’ve enjoyed speaking in English. I took pride in being fluent in the language at school and even college. I often said I think in English. I had no issues giving presentations, making points in meetings, or having casual conversations at the workplace.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Term 01 | Leadership Assignments</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/assignments/term-01-leadership-assignments/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/assignments/term-01-leadership-assignments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the assignments was to make a video about ourself. I was quite apprehensive at first. But I realised it&amp;rsquo;s a good practice to concisely tell a story about yourself. This is my attempt at telling a story about how I got into science communication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/u5gpWx6yQP4?si=jGN61-DxEP5tDXFP&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Term 01 | Statistics Group Assignments</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/assignments/term-01-stats-group-assignments/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/assignments/term-01-stats-group-assignments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the course, we had 4 group assignments, which required us to use statistical tools like z-score, t-test, chi-squared test, etc in various scenarios. I decided to use Python to do all analyses. Looking back, it was a nice way to practice coding while also learning new concepts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;notebook-links&#34;&gt;Notebook Links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assignment 01 (Kilgore Production Analysis): &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/ShweataNHegde/a4203e663b0f1cea6cb9c52e35258a1c&#34;&gt;https://gist.github.com/ShweataNHegde/a4203e663b0f1cea6cb9c52e35258a1c&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assignment 02 (Pronto Delivery): &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/ShweataNHegde/abd7b814af4c16cd376747fdf35f2dac&#34;&gt;https://gist.github.com/ShweataNHegde/abd7b814af4c16cd376747fdf35f2dac&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assignment 03 (Cyril Burt: Fraud or Not?): &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/ShweataNHegde/d421bb33b3f77c06b8023d179266b55a&#34;&gt;https://gist.github.com/ShweataNHegde/d421bb33b3f77c06b8023d179266b55a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assignment 04 (Teachers Fraud?): &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/ShweataNHegde/1f3f824c37a1a0ddd37ab7f4271c2746&#34;&gt;https://gist.github.com/ShweataNHegde/1f3f824c37a1a0ddd37ab7f4271c2746&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Term 01| Statistics Individual Assignment</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/assignments/term-01-stats-ind-assignment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/assignments/term-01-stats-ind-assignment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Through the course, I learnt about various statistical tools and concept. But I also explored how to run them in Python. So, it only makes sense for my final report to be an interactive Python file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34; data-lang=&#34;python&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;# Import packages&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;kn&#34;&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nn&#34;&gt;scipy.stats&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;kn&#34;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;norm&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;kn&#34;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nn&#34;&gt;matplotlib.pyplot&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nn&#34;&gt;plt&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;kn&#34;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nn&#34;&gt;numpy&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nn&#34;&gt;np&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;kn&#34;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nn&#34;&gt;random&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;kn&#34;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nn&#34;&gt;seaborn&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nn&#34;&gt;sns&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h1 id=&#34;part-a&#34;&gt;Part A&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Choose three of the four following statistical tools (A.1 – A.4). For each of your chosen three, write a short response exhibiting your understanding of the tool (250 words maximum each).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
